Contact

cscorales@msn.com

www.linkedin.com/in/clintonc-716576139 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Critical Care Medicine
Advanced Cardiac Life Support
(ACLS)

Medical Oncology

Certifications

Critical Care RN (Adult) (CCRN-A)
Acute Care NP (ACNP-BC)
Advanced Practice RN (APRN)
FCCS - Fundamentals of Critical
Care Support

Clinton Corales

MSN, APRN, ACNP-BC, CCRN Advanced Practice Provider Houston, Texas Area

Summary

Experienced Acute Care NP with a demonstrated history of working in the Acute and Critical Care environment. Skilled in Critical Care Medicine, Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS), Rapid Response, Internal Medicine, Medical Oncology and Nursing Education. Strong healthcare services professional with a MSN degree in Acute Care NP, from The University of Texas HSC - Houston.

Experience

Houston Methodist
Acute Care NP - Critical Care
July 2016 - Present (3 years 11 months)
Sugar Land, Texas

- •Provide comprehensive care to CV surgery/SICU/MICU/Acute care patients.
- •Perform H&Ps/critical care consults and develop a treatment plan.
- •Procedure capable (intubations, central lines, arterial lines, HD access, PICC).
- •Respond to Code blue, STEMI, Rapid Response and Sepsis calls.

Grand Canyon University
Adjunct Clinical Faculty - Graduate
August 2017 - August 2018 (1 year 1 month)

College of Nursing and Healthcare Professions - Graduate Education - MSN Acute Care NP Track

- •Site Supervisor for Houston area clinical facilities
- •Advanced Health Assessment and Diagnostic Reasoning Course Evaluator

MD Anderson Cancer Center 12 years 11 months

Advanced Practice Provider - Critical Care June 2015 - June 2016 (1 year 1 month) Houston, Texas

Advanced Practice Provider - Sarcoma Medical Oncology

Page 1 of 2

January 2014 - June 2015 (1 year 6 months)

Houston, Texas

- •Provide quality care throughout the oncologic disease process; diagnosis, treatment, rehabilitation, palliative, and terminal care.
- •Prevent, minimize and manage toxicities/symptoms related to the disease or treatment in collaboration with allied team and oncologist.
- •Attend and present clinical cases during weekly team review meetings / tumor board.
- •Perform credentialed procedures.

Team/Operational Leader

August 2003 - January 2014 (10 years 6 months)

Houston, Texas

- •Evidence Based Unit Resource
- •M.E.R.I.T. Responder
- •Editorial staff for ICU newsletter
- •Resource for Picis, EV1000, SLED, LiDCO
- Preceptor / Skills validator
- Advisory board / ICU nurse council

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

Adjunct Clinical Instructor - Undergraduate August 2014 - August 2015 (1 year 1 month)

Houston, Texas

College of Nursing

Memorial Hermann Health System
CCU / IMCU / CVRR Charge
August 2000 - August 2003 (3 years 1 month)

Houston, Texas

Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

Master of Science in Nursing, Acute Care NP · (2012)